Dharmik Abhangi

Surat, Gujarat, India



abhangidharmik@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/dharmik-abhangi

Summary

I was born and grew up in India. I love to travel across peaceful places like Munnar in Kerala. I love to read books that can help me to grow my mindset.

Developed user interactive website with A-Grade performance for an Indian Service-based startup with an open-source facility where they can upload their 3D models for public use.

Developer Expertise

1## HTML5 / HTML

2## CSS3 + SASS

3## javascript

4## React

5## Redux

6## Tailwind CSS & Bootstrap

7## Node

8## MongoDB + Firebase

9## Typescript (Learning)

Soft Skills

- ◆ Effective Communication
- ◆ Team Work
- ◆ Emotional Intelligence
- Leadership
- ◆ Effective Remote Working
- Stakeholder Management

Al Skills

- 1. Prompt Design
- 2. Fine Tuning

Experience



Graduate Engineer Trainee - Manufacturing Planning

Godrej & Boyce Mfg. Co. Ltd.

Sep 2022 - Mar 2023 (7 months)

- Developed a very efficient plan to make sure that no resources and time is being wasted and used in an efficient way
- Reduced the bottleneck of the machining process by planning all the activities according to the priority and cycle time

- Implemented a standard tooling system where all tools can be used for different projects

Full Stack Developer Trainee

Pesto Tech

Jul 2022 - Dec 2022 (6 months)

- Learned HTML5, CSS3 and Web Accessibility
- Mastered Javascript with advanced concepts like Closures, Promise, Prototypes, AJAX, etc.
- Developed skills to create SPA using react, redux and tailwind CSS.
- Practiced DSA concepts and exercises to develop Problem-Solving skills.
- Developed a handful experience on creating API Using NodeJS
- Developed a skill in Git and version control system



Computer Aided Design Designer

Ratnam Fixtures

Jan 2022 - May 2022 (5 months)

- Design well-dressed Furniture products with high-quality render images for clients to get real-life visualization.

🗚 Mechanical Team member

GTU Robotics Club

Jul 2020 - Dec 2021 (1 year 6 months)

- Developed Arrow throwing mechanism which led my team to the international by securing 1st runner up and 2nd runner up in DD Robocon National out of 100+ teams overall in India.
- Fabricated and Developed the Robot which uses the same mechanism to throw the robot with high structural stability and controlled pneumatic systems.
- Developed skills for additive manufacturing and used that technology in our robot to reduce the weight of robot with achieving expected result.

Education



Gujarat Technological University (GTU)

Bachelor's degree, Mechanical Engineering

Jul 2018 - Apr 2022

- Learned Basic Engineering and ethics concepts like Project management, Operation research, Ethical Engineering, etc.
- Developed knowledge in the field of manufacturing and Production Industry.

⊗z™ Zero To Mastery Academy

Course, Full stack development

Mar 2023 - Present

Licenses & Certifications

React - The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux - Udemy

UC-11bf3d23-059d-457f-884e-d603c0ccc3b3

- in JavaScript: Web Workers LinkedIn
- in JavaScript and AJAX: Integration Techniques LinkedIn

Skills

SASS • Socket.io • Firebase • prompt design • Fine Tuning • Testing • Test Driven Development • SQL • Kinematics • styled-components